Hello, welcome everybody. How is everybody doing today? This is going to be an
안녕하세요, 여러분 모두 환영합니다. 오늘 다들 어떠신가요? 이번 수업은
awesome listening and speaking class. I'm so glad that all of you are here. Welcome
정말 멋진 듣기 말하기 수업이 될 겁니다. 여러분 모두 여기 와주셔서 정말 기쁩니다. 모두
everybody. Like training a muscle. The brain is not a muscle but we build
환영합니다. 마치 근육을 단련하는 것과 같아요. 뇌는 근육이 아니지만 우리는 연결을
connections. We build stronger connections and so our aim today is for your
만들어냅니다. 우리는 더 강력한 연결을 만들죠. 그래서 오늘 우리의 목표는 여러분의 답변이
answers to try to be natural, fluent and clear. You might notice that I'm
자연스럽고, 유창하며, 명확하도록 노력하는 것입니다. 제가 여러분이 말하는 동안
typing as you speak. Try to look at some of these corrections that I'm making
타이핑하는 것을 눈치채셨을 수도 있습니다. 제가 만들고 있는 이 수정 사항들 중 일부를 살펴보세요.
some of them are just rephrasing of what you could say maybe a little bit
어떤 것들은 여러분이 조금 더 잘 말할 수 있는 표현으로 단순히 바꿔 말한 것입니다.
better. It improve your fluency. But I don't want it to interrupt your speaking.
이것이 여러분의 유창성을 향상시킬 겁니다. 하지만 이것이 여러분의 말하기를 방해하지는 않았으면 합니다.
Just try to focus on being natural, fluent and clear. The whole goal is to
그저 자연스럽고, 유창하며, 명확하게 말하는 데 집중하도록 노력하세요. 전체 목표는
understand and be understood. Here's a question. What's one thing you already feel
이해하고 이해받는 것입니다. 여기 질문이 있습니다. 영어를 말할 때 이미
good about when speaking English? I don't know. That's a hard one. Okay, so I
자신 있다고 느끼는 한 가지는 무엇인가요? 모르겠어요. 어려운 질문이네요. 네, 그래서 제 생각엔
think it's like now when I speak English, I don't feel like embarrassed if
지금 영어를 말할 때, 누가 저를 수정해줘도
something somebody correct me. So I think that's what something I feel good
부끄럽다고 느끼지 않는 것 같아요. 그래서 그게 지금 제가 자신 있다고 느끼는 부분인 것 같습니다.
now. That comes with experience really. That does help. And the next one, what's
그건 정말 경험에서 나오는 거죠. 그게 도움이 됩니다. 다음 질문입니다. 영어 면접에서
one area you think might be challenging in an English interview and why? I think
어떤 부분이 어려울 것 같고, 그 이유는 무엇인가요? 제 생각엔
it will be like the new vocabulary and (I) have to express or like as you mentioned
새로운 어휘가 될 것 같고, 또 표현해야 하거나 선생님께서 언급하신 것처럼
trying to put what I'm thinking in something like a more clear and in short.
제가 생각하는 것을 좀 더 명확하고 간결하게 정리하려고 노력하는 것이요.
*In size. Yes. Okay. And trying to say something clearly and concisely.
간결하게요. 네. 알겠습니다. 무언가를 명확하고 간결하게 말하려고 노력하는 것이죠.
All right. I agree. All of these things can be improved too the more you do it. So we
네. 동의합니다. 이 모든 것들도 더 많이 할수록 향상될 수 있습니다. 그래서 우리는
could try to improve how we say things to make them more clear or concise in
오늘 수업에서 우리가 말하는 방식을 개선하여 더 명확하거나 간결하게 만들도록 노력할 수 있습니다.
today's lesson. One of the most popular interview questions that they ask is
그들이 묻는 가장 인기 있는 면접 질문 중 하나는
tell me about yourself. They want you to open up. They want you to break the ice.
"자신에 대해 말해주세요"입니다. 그들은 여러분이 마음을 열기를 원합니다. 그들은 여러분이 어색함을 깨기를 원합니다.
They've asked this question a million times. Some people use this in order to
그들은 이 질문을 백만 번은 물어봤을 겁니다. 어떤 사람들은 이것을 상대방에게
impress the other person or like I said, break the ice. What do they really want?
깊은 인상을 주거나, 제가 말했듯이, 어색함을 깨기 위해 사용합니다. 그들이 정말로 원하는 것은 무엇일까요?
What they really want is something brief, right? One to two minutes. A relevant
그들이 정말로 원하는 것은 간결한 무언가입니다, 그렇죠? 1분에서 2분 정도요. 여러분의 전문적인 배경,
summary of your professional background, your skills, career goals, these
기술, 경력 목표에 대한 관련성 있는 요약, 이러한
essential things that they need to know. Why? Because if this is the first question,
그들이 알아야 할 필수적인 것들입니다. 왜냐고요? 만약 이것이 첫 번째 질문이라면,
they need to have a very good one, a very strong positive first impression of
그들은 여러분에 대해 매우 좋은, 매우 강력하고 긍정적인 첫인상을 가져야 하기 때문입니다.
you for that first question they ask. Here's an activity for your dream job. What
그들이 묻는 첫 번째 질문에 대해서요. 여기 여러분의 꿈의 직업에 대한 활동이 있습니다. "자신에 대해
are one to two key achievements or skills you'd highlight and your tell me about
말해주세요" 답변에서 강조하고 싶은 한두 가지 주요 성과나 기술은 무엇인가요?
yourself answer. What are two skills or achievements you would highlight? I think it
강조하고 싶은 두 가지 기술이나 성과는 무엇인가요? 제 생각엔
will be something related with decision making. And I think the other one will be
의사 결정과 관련된 것일 것 같습니다. 그리고 다른 하나는
with like, I don't know how to say it's like when you learn something by
음, 어떻게 말해야 할지 모르겠는데, 혼자서 무언가를 배울 때와 같은 것입니다.
yourself. So one skill is that you are good at making decisions and that you
그러니까 한 가지 기술은 의사 결정을 잘한다는 것이고, 또 다른 하나는
and the other one is that you know a lot about yourself. The other one is like if
자기 자신에 대해 많이 안다는 것이군요. 다른 하나는 만약
I don't if I don't know something, I look for it until I know it. Okay. And I
제가 무언가를 모르면, 알 때까지 찾아본다는 것입니다. 알겠습니다. 그리고 저는
learn, I try to learn by myself before I on your own. Right, so learn on my
스스로 배우려고 노력합니다, 도움을 요청하기 전에요. 스스로 배우는군요. 네, 그러니까 도움을 요청하기 전에
own before I asked for help. So you consider yourself to be an autonomous
스스로 배운다는 거죠. 그럼 스스로를 자율적인 사람이라고 생각하시는군요.
person. You're capable of working alone autonomously. Is that right? Yes, I can
혼자서 자율적으로 일할 수 있다는 말씀이시죠. 맞나요? 네, 저는
work both, but yeah, I try to look first by myself. And I think this would
둘 다 할 수 있지만, 네, 먼저 스스로 찾아보려고 노력합니다. 그리고 제 생각에 이것은
highlight the fact that you are capable of making good decisions that they're
여러분이 좋은 결정을 내릴 수 있다는 사실을 강조할 것입니다. 그들이 여러분이 하는 일을
not going to have to micromanage what you do that you trust that you can find
일일이 간섭할 필요가 없을 것이라는 점, 여러분이 올바른 답을 찾을 수 있다고 믿는다는 점,
the correct answer that you're not going to be a burden on them and that you
여러분이 그들에게 부담이 되지 않을 것이라는 점, 그리고 여러분이 필요한 기술을 가지고 있다는 점을요.
have the necessary skills. I think that's a good way to make a good first
제 생각에 그것이 좋은 첫인상을 주는 좋은 방법인 것 같습니다.
impression. Yeah, yes. So we have some different phrases that we can use to answer
네, 그렇습니다. 그래서 이 질문에 답하는 데 사용할 수 있는 몇 가지 다른 표현들이 있습니다.
this question. For example, if I were to tell someone about myself, I'd say my
예를 들어, 만약 제가 누군가에게 제 자신에 대해 말한다면, 저는 제 이름은 데이비드 브라운이라고 말할 겁니다.
name is David Brown. I'm passionate about teaching English as a second
저는 제2외국어로서의 영어 교육에 열정적입니다.
language. I've had about 24,000 sessions online with students from all around
저는 전 세계 학생들과 약 24,000번의 온라인 수업을 진행했습니다.
the world. I have taught younger students in middle school and high school
저는 중학교와 고등학교의 어린 학생들을 가르쳤고,
really identify with the work that I do in my free time. I think about it as
제가 하는 일에 정말로 동질감을 느낍니다. 제 자유 시간에도 그것에 대해 생각합니다.
well. I like to spend time with my family and friends and dream about new
저는 가족 및 친구들과 시간을 보내는 것을 좋아하고 새로운 기술에 대해
technology. I don't know. That's what I might have a job interview in a
꿈꿉니다. 모르겠네요. 제가 곧 취업 면접이 있을지도 모르는데, 그게 제가 할 말일 겁니다.
little bit. Norma, tell me, do you think that would make a good first impression?
노르마 학생, 말해주세요, 그것이 좋은 첫인상을 줄 것이라고 생각하나요?
Yes. Oh, I hope so. I don't know if this lesson is better for me or for you
네. 아, 그랬으면 좋겠네요. 이 수업이 저에게 더 좋은 건지 아니면 학생에게 더 좋은 건지 모르겠어요,
actually. Thank you. Thank you. Norma, this lesson is free. All right, so what made
사실은요. 감사합니다. 감사합니다. 노르마 학생, 이 수업은 무료입니다. 자, 그럼 무엇이
that example easy to understand? I think I spoke a little bit too fast, but what
그 예시를 이해하기 쉽게 만들었을까요? 제가 말을 좀 빨리 한 것 같기도 한데, 어떻게
do you think? What made that example easy to understand? No, actually, what I
생각하세요? 무엇이 그 예시를 이해하기 쉽게 만들었나요? 아니요, 사실 제가
like listen (heard) was about the time that you have the experience that you have.
들은 것은 선생님께서 가지신 경험에 관한 것이었습니다.
And also I can see like with the range of age that you can work. So
그리고 또한 선생님께서 함께 일하실 수 있는 연령대의 범위도 알 수 있었습니다. 그래서
I know that you can do it with older or younger. And also that you are somebody
선생님께서 나이가 많거나 어린 사람들과도 일하실 수 있다는 것을 알아요. 그리고 또한 선생님께서
that takes care of our family. Okay, also, yeah, you have some good listening
가족을 돌보는 분이라는 것도요. 네, 또한, 네, 이미 좋은 듣기 능력을 가지고 계시네요.
skills already. What I, instead of saying what I listen*, you could say what I, what
제가, "what I listen*"이라고 말하는 대신, "what I, what I heard"라고 말할 수 있습니다.
I heard rather, you could say what I heard was about the experience that you
오히려, "제가 들은 것은 선생님께서 가지신 경험에 관한 것이었고,
have and also see the age ranges you can work for. So I know you can work with
또한 선생님께서 일하실 수 있는 연령대도 알 수 있었습니다. 그래서 선생님께서 더 어리거나
younger or older people. I understood you perfectly. All right, so we also have
나이 많은 사람들과도 일하실 수 있다는 것을 알아요."라고 말할 수 있습니다. 저는 완벽하게 이해했습니다. 자, 그럼 우리에게는 또한
this other really big question. It's always asked when you're asked what are
이 다른 정말 큰 질문이 있습니다. 항상 묻는 질문이죠, "당신의 강점은 무엇인가요?"라고 물을 때요.
your strengths? We have a chance to shine. We can show other people what we've
우리는 빛날 기회가 있습니다. 우리는 다른 사람들에게 우리가 가진 것을 보여줄 수 있습니다.
got. What are your strengths, Norma? So you can, but what, but it's going to be
노르마 학생의 강점은 무엇인가요? 그래서 여러분은, 하지만 무엇을, 하지만 이것에 대해 구체적이어야 합니다, 그렇죠?
specific about this, right? Because we can, we can tell someone that we are good
왜냐하면 우리는, 우리는 누군가에게 우리가 좋은 경청자라고 말할 수 있지만,
listener, but when were you a good listener? And what situation can you be more
언제 좋은 경청자였나요? 그리고 어떤 상황에서 더 구체적으로 말할 수 있나요?
specific? This can really help. If you can demonstrate specific, specific
이것이 정말 도움이 될 수 있습니다. 만약 여러분이 구체적인, 구체적인 예를
examples. And then when you're asked, what is your greatest weakness? You can
제시할 수 있다면요. 그리고 나서 "당신의 가장 큰 약점은 무엇인가요?"라는 질문을 받으면, 여러분은
choose a real minor weakness you're actively improving. So this shows that
적극적으로 개선하고 있는 사소한 실제 약점을 선택할 수 있습니다. 이것은 여러분이
you're honest. And they say that you should avoid cliche is like, I'm a
정직하다는 것을 보여줍니다. 그리고 그들은 "저는 완벽주의자예요"와 같은 진부한 표현은
perfectionist, unless you can generally back it up. Are you really a perfectionist?
피해야 한다고 말합니다, 여러분이 그것을 일반적으로 뒷받침할 수 없다면 말이죠. 여러분은 정말 완벽주의자인가요?